good morning thank you for joining us uh
has anything changed in your approach in
your portfolio in your outlook post the
budget not really I I thought the budget
was a no- nonsense budget um the economy
continues to open up I think the first
time in two years my kids are going to
school every week so that's a that's an
undecided positive if you ask me not
just for my children but children all
across the country and the entire
ecosystem of you know vendors which
which survives by by catering to our
schools so the economy is improving the
fiscal position uh is better than I
thought it would be honestly I think
that the budget painted a far better
fiscal position than I thought it would
be uh the the the short-term items that
you mentioned around uh uh oil prices
and and bond deals are there but we've
never really lost too much sleep about
that our Focus has been invest in strong
well-run companies and benefit from the
the the underlying compounding and great
franchises in this in this massive
economy I I fully Endo that idea s of
you you don't look at macros when you
invest you look at individual companies
and your understanding of the business
that's the unique aspect of marceles but
macros do matter if cost of capital goes
to 7 or 7 and a half it will have an
impact on demand it will have an impact
on valuations it will have an impact on
flows uh at what point in time you would
say that look while I continue to focus
on micro which is individual companies
the micro for me something I cannot be
now
ignoring so Nik there's two ways to
understand macro right the the way we
understand macro is the structural story
so for example uh India's 10year
Government Bond deal uh in 2004 2005 was
177% today it is 6.7 and we are fretting
that it might go to seven right so that
for me is macro that you have a
structural downtrend over 10 15 years a
10% 10 percentage points drop in your
cost of capital that's what transforms
countries and if I look at that
structure Al type of macro I don't see
what what I should exactly lose sleep
about the financialization of our
country continues your channel your
viewers our clients are all proof of
that financialization as
financialization continues cost of
capital structurally continues to go
down sure there will be a Fed hike three
fed hikes four fed hikes but that's not
going to be a structural story those are
those are cyclical waves and our job is
not to second guess and nobody who's
watching this should be trying to second
guess cyclical waves and trying to make
money from that because that is a
absolute Fool's erend focus on the
structural story absolutely macro
matters but structural stories matter
the cyclical Stories the noise noise is
oil price a what will be the oil price
next week next month that doesn't matter
so much it doesn't matter for two
reasons a that is a that is a mean
reverting story it's a cyclical story
there's plenty of noise in the oil price
and B uh structurally the oil price is
not going to stay high not will it stay
low oil price is structurally tend to
hover around $50 to $80 so focus on
macro stories which are structural
rather than rather than noise macro
stories rather than cyclical macro
stories s hi there morning I'm going to
get stock specific because the last time
we interacted with you you spoke about
picking out stocks that have strong
volume growth and are growing very
strongly when it comes to their free
cash flows so you know invest heavily in
midcaps you said like astral poly Dr L
relaxo page Industries Etc could you
just walk us through some of those names
tell us what the performance has been
like and if there's anything else within
uh the midcap universe that you think
fits this bill right so I think we've
discussed building materials on several
18 hour shows in the past so let me
focus on three other three other aspects
of the midcap universe where we are
investing fairly enthusiastically in our
in our Rising Giants product two
disclaimers one uh every stock I mention
is is a is a part of Marcel's portfolio
and two my money my family's money my
parents's money is invested via Marcel's
products in these stocks so so just to
be very clear about what I'm going to
talk about so so the part of midcap
where we are getting even more excited
now than we were say three months ago is
is midcap lenders uh with asset quality
troubles for lenders uh largely behind
them we are seeing midcap lenders post
not just loan book growth but
profitability growth which is north of
25 % so cha mandam and AAS financiers
we're building larger positions there
than we hither to hither to had done uh
also IC Lombard I know it's not a lender
it's a general insurer uh IC Lombard is
a is a stock where we're continuing to
build a larger position in our Flagship
product which is uh which is consistent
Compounders U moving on to a second area
Specialty Chemicals has been a big
favorite of us over the last couple of
years of for obvious reasons as input
cost pressures have built up there has
been margin pressure in Specialty
Chemicals as I just said five minutes
back I reckon input cost pressures are
transient uh the volume growth and the
market share gains that we are seeing
Indian Specialty Chemicals uh uh deliver
I reona are more structural so our
position build up in our midcap products
now in companies like alky amines and
and GMM fraer continues a base and the
third area is is uh is the is the IT
services space TCS long-standing
favorite but in midcap
L&T technology Services uh continues to
be continues to be a company where we're
building a larger position similar story
somewhat to finan with in midcap IT
specialist providers who can deliver uh
uh 30 40% free cash flow growth 20 30%
Pat growth are not that not that common
remember the larger IT services
companies uh find it hard to deliver 20
30% pad growth consistently we think L&T
technology Services has a product Suite
around engineering R&D which will give
it a Solid 5 six year growth Runway and
hence that's that's part of a our midcap
buildup I know you flagged off midcap it
but Sor what about New Age tech
companies the real hot space to be in
you know you saw a lot of uh um you know
you saw a lot of fervor within this
space in the first few months after
their listing then they bore the brunt
of the uh you know volatility in the
equity markets lots of selling pressure
when you think names like zomato PTM
naika P&B fintech Etc um what's the
what's the Outlook as to how they've
performed and where you
stand so we've had a look at uh last
year's crop of IPOs I think discussed on
your channels we've been looking at last
year's IPOs quite carefully uh honestly
the the tech names we haven't yet been
able to convince ourselves that there
are sustainable competitive advantages
there we are very conventional
oldfashioned investors if we don't see
even say forget free cash flows forget
profitability if we can't even see
operating profit operating margins uh uh
then it's very difficult to convince
ourselves as a franchise there sure
you've ra raised a lot of money and
you've built whatever gmv or whatever
the metrics are but uh if you're not
able to deliver operating profitability
then difficult for us to convince
ourselves you built a franchise we've
done a fair bit of granular analysis
actually as to why many of these
companies are not able to deliver
operating profits and our Reckoning is
many of these franchises are flattering
to deceive um ironically out of the IPOs
last year the one that we have built a
substantial position is Tarson it's a
provider of uh of lab equipment and
equipment to the diagnostic Labs so Dr
lalpathlabs for example used to be a
Tarson customer so Tarson has built a a
business with 50 50% evida margins 30%
Pat margins um in an industry which is
around 1,200 crores but but as the
Specialty Chemicals industry and the
Pharma industry grows we reckon the lab
equipment space will grow similarly
because they'll supply to the the the
Specialty Chemicals companies who
internally supply to the Pharma
companies Tarson is the dominant player
in this lab Market the small company to
the 300 CR Top Line but 30% Pat margins
and our discussions the dealers and
Distributors of Tarson suggest uh that
this is a uh well-run motored company
with very few competitors in the Indian
market
good morning s this is Nara so when you
were talking about the new stocks and
you know you gave the disclosure as well
but with the new stock ideas that you
talked about I couldn't help but notice
um the new hot pack at the moment the
metal storying uh was missing from that
uh are these not great franchises that
are being built with decarbonization
being the theme around the world I know
the Jew is divided when it comes to this
story
so in a way this goes back to the
beginning of our discussion with nikun
right with any metals and Mining Company
right not just in India the world over
right any metals and Mining Company um
it's very difficult for them to decouple
themselves from the global commodity
cycle typically the share price of these
companies has a 70% correlation with the
underlying metal prices on the London
Metal Exchange so effectively when you
buy a metals and Mining Company you are
basically betting on the lme metal price
which to my mind is not a area where we
in marceles have any have any
competitive Advantage how are we
supposed to predict metal prices 6
months end 12 months end and if we can't
do that uh we can't really take our
clients's money and invest it in these
stocks okay so you're staying out to the
metal story I thought I'd ask you this
because it has turned out to be a hot
pack the other thing S I wanted to ask
you about you know you've spoken a lot
about for example the great franchise of
HDFC Bank how it is been uh building up
its market share Etc but the HDFC group
but then 2021 or the early signs of it
in this year not so encouraging right on
the other hand you got public sector
Banks like uh an SBI which has
outperformed the market uh the
expectation is the public sector banks
will be outperforming will you be making
adjustments in your portfolio or is this
a space that you would be looking at
especially when the other franchise you
bet on in the financial spaces Bajaj
finser but we've been talking so much
about PE compression questions as
well so I've lived in Indiana now for 13
years I've looked at sbi's numbers for
last 20 years going back 20 years I
haven't seen them deliver a return on
Equity above their cost of equity in
this Century uh so when they do so we'll
obviously be happy to happy to have a
look because again staying with
fundamentals difficult to take uh in the
money from hardworking families and say
I will take your money and I'll invest
it in a in a bank which doesn't deliver
a return on equity above cost of equity
on the other hand let's focus on HDFC
Bank uh they have gained more market
share than the entire private sector
banking space plus SBI put together in
the last three years three years ago
market share was 7% today it's 10% add
up all the private sector Banks add up
SBI in the three years they haven't got
remotely close to HDFC Bank uh asset
quality net npas different League to any
other large private sector Bank too or
to SBI uh net interest margins obviously
very good because of their uh famous
Kasa franchise so um you know unless I'm
very very obsessed about short-term
movements I don't see why we and
marceles or indeed anybody else holding
HDFC Bank there Bank shares out there
should lose sleep uh uh impeccable
operating performance quarter after
quarter uh uh and 3% Market sh rains in
three years 3% Market Che gain in three
years I haven't seen any Bank do that
anywhere in the world that is phenomenal
at this scale to go from 7% to 10%
through covid through the disruptions we
had is phenomenal um just to put it in
perspective kotak bank's market share is
2 and a half% that means in the last
three years HDFC bank has added on a
bank much larger than KK Bank um but
obviously those who focus in the work in
the stock market focus on noise and news
flow we don't do that we focus on the
fundamentals and keep our eye on the
ball so just for the benefit of our
viewers I know we've discussed this much
but you know this topic keeps on coming
out again and again there's nothing
wrong in buying good quality businesses
but good quality businesses may not be
this great stock and the classic example
which you've spoken about which you've
defended which I defended which
everybody knows but for those who don't
know is that un
example un time wise correction company
went through okay growth but the stock
did nothing could that be the story for
HDFC bank because last two years in a
bull market the stock has underperformed
last one year returns are
negative so so people keep citing these
stories I think another one story I keep
getting is infosis share price in 2008
was the same uh share price that it had
in the year 2000 um and and we keep
hearing these stories um uh if you see
if you see the Indian market in the last
20 years you and I will struggle to find
any company and happy for people out
there to send send us proof uh in emails
uh uh in the last years I haven't found
any company in the Indian market where
Pat grows at 20% year after year and the
share price doesn't grow for obvious
reasons right if a company's delivering
Pat growth of 20% year after year uh
then every four years basically the
company's doubling uh uh the the
business doubling the Pat and it'll be
crazy for the stock market not to take
heed what you do get nikun I completely
admit is if a great franchise becomes a
mediocre franchise if a great franchise
underperforms from from a business
perspective the pat stops growing at 20%
the pat becomes single digit Pat growth
then obviously the share price stagnates
so the so so the point we all have to
recognize is if we get the if we from a
investment perspective if we get the
quality wrong I we thought this is a
great franchise but actually it's a
mediocre franchise then of course it'll
underperform and that's the main risk to
our style of investing and it's a risk
we have to be very Vigilant about that
we are genuinely investing in companies
which continue to be producing great
results and if the results are medoc
over an extended period obviously we
will underperform and that's the reason
I focus on the business rather than
focusing on the stock price the stock
price tells us nothing uh it's one of
the biggest ironies of investing the
stock price has zero information
value how will LIC IPO change the
Dynamics for the life insurance sector
why am I asking you this because you own
HDFC life why am I asking you this is
because this is one sector where you've
had a covid pain this is one sector
where insurance companies are struggling
to increase premiums
also right so if you see let's take
address both issues um lic's market
share losses uh these of V the private
sector life insurers are a very similar
story to say how public sector lenders
have lost market share to the private
sector lenders right so it's a repeat of
the basically the same Paradigm uh uh in
life insurance we see a replay of what's
happened to the public sector Banks over
the last 20 years but as we also
discussing SBI remains a formidable
lender and therefore simith bik same
token LC remains a formidable uh life
insurer so I'm not so sure the IPO will
change the operating Dynamics in the
life insurance industry you know the
interaction that with the say the life
of the manufacturers have with the
distribution and the dealership
community and I don't think the Public's
perception of LC will change but the
Public's perception is LC is a sound
insurer a reliable insurer I think that
perception will will sustain very nicely
for the years to come um Vis A HDFC life
um growth in embedded value growth in
premiums has been solid so even the
month of January which was a pretty soft
month for other insurers and as you are
alluding to recent quarters have been
soft for other life insurers hdfc's
growth in embedded value the growth in
uh uh profitability in the business has
been very steady around the 20% mark and
um and we we have you know we've really
really nothing but admiration for the
way uh the operating uh the operations
of the business have been run by Viba
and the broader team at HDFC live amitab
CH in his HDFC life years did a fabulous
job I think VI and team have taken it
Forward uh operating metrics are
impeccable and to our mind this is a
class apart HDFC life is a class apart
in Indian life insurance uh much like uh
uh HDFC Bank in the context of private
sector
Banks so we discussed banking days you
discuss Specialty Chemicals you
discussed why you're not looking too
much into macros as well but I would
like to just ask a little bit about the
consumer names and the franchises that
you've been betting on right from a
Titan to a pidilite um we've seen the
third quarter numbers as well inflation
is on the rise there is all this talk of
PE compression so are you still going to
bet on the consumer stories with these
and nestl or how are you doing
it yes so I think again uh the
performance is
self-explanatory I think Titan if you
even if you take a two-year gagar look
through Co because Co obviously flatters
the performance of Titan even if you do
a two-year kagar I think the business is
doing Top Line and bottom line growing
at 25 30% and remember Titan's grown
free cash flows at 30% kagar for 20
years similarly pedite actually
interestingly the two firms you
mentioned have grown free cash flows at
30% kagar for 20 years that means
they've grown free cash flows around
150x over the last 20 years this is just
no incredible I doubt too many companies
in the world can claim what Titan and
pedite can claim that they've grown 150
fold in two year 20 years now uh pite's
case operating performance is solid I
think they did around 20% excluding the
Acquisitions they they're gunning out
around 20% growth in operating
profitability um yes there is operating
there is input cost pressure on pedite
um but that's again transient I don't
think V prices will carry on sustaining
at these levels uh the input cost
pressures are transient the market share
gains the efficiency improvements are
are structural uh that's that has really
been Del light story for the last 10 15
years consistent improvement improvement
in working capital Cycles Improvement in
in uh in operating cash flow driven by
underlying efficiency improvements it's
a leaner fitter business than it was 10
years ago and and that's what you know
that's what makes us money uh if a
business is growing let's say
conservatively 10x in 10 years 25% cash
flow compounding means 10x growth in 10
years even if the P multiples moves a
little bit either we not going to lose
sleep focus is focus on businesses which
can do 10x in 10 years in terms of free
cash flow compounding let the PE
multiple Merchants focus on their PE
multiples okay so that's H SAR mukarji
says he plays um 2020 Cricket with the
mindset of a test player thanks so much
for joining us live today on the market
or was a pleasure to host
you for an earnings call now and we're
going to do that